Welcome to the program,
brothers and sisters!
兄弟姉妹 ようこそ！
今月のプログラムでは—
During the next hour,
you will hear the story of a brother
かつて大統領の警護をしていた兄弟の
経験をお聞きします
who previously protected
the president of a country.
兄弟は 神の民の間にある愛を見て—
But seeing the love among God’s people
made him refocus his life
自分の人生を見つめなおし—
to bearing witness
about the Sovereign of the universe.
宇宙主権者の証人となりました
わたしたちは 世界的な
兄弟関係を大切にしています
We cherish our international brotherhood.
Our brothers and sisters
in the former Soviet Union took great risks
旧ソビエトの兄弟姉妹たちは
冷戦の間 危険を冒しつつ—
during the Cold War to convey their love
地球の裏側にいる仲間の証人たちに
愛を届けました
to fellow Witnesses
on the other side of the globe.
エホバへの愛は 裏表のある
生活を避けるようわたしたちを促します
Does our love for Jehovah motivate us
to avoid living a double life?
This dramatization
will remind us of key principles
このドラマは サタンの世に
引き寄せられる誘惑に遭うとき—
to protect us when we are tempted
to draw closer to Satan’s world.
わたしたちを保護する
大切な原則を思い起こさせます
This is the July program
of JW Broadcasting!
7月のJW Broadcastingです！
In the book
Insight on the Scriptures,
「洞察」の本の
「クリスチャン」の項によればー
under the heading “Christian,”
クリスチャンであることには—
it makes clear that claiming to be Christian
信仰を告白する以上のことが
関係しています
requires more than simply
a mere confession of faith.
それは 名目だけのクリスチャンに
なるのとは異なります
It is more than
being a nominal Christian
—a Christian in name only.
For example,
according to the Bible,
例えば聖書によれば—
it is necessary that belief
信仰は 言葉だけでなく
業に表われている必要があります
be demonstrated by works,
not just words.
And since we were born
as sinners,
わたしたちは
罪のうちに生まれたので—
those who become Christians
need to repent,
クリスチャンになるために
悔い改め 転向し 献身し—
to turn around,
to dedicate their lives to Jehovah,
エホバを崇拝して
お仕えし—
to worship and serve him,
水のバプテスマを
受けなければなりません
and then to submit
to water baptism.
さらに 淫行 偶像崇拝 血の使用から
自分の身を清く保つ必要があります
They must keep themselves
clean from fornication,
from idolatry,
and from consuming blood.
They are to strip off
the old personality,
古い人格を脱ぎ捨てて—
激発的な怒り 卑わいなことば
うそ 盗み 酔酒—
including such things
as fits of anger, obscene talk,
lying, stealing, drunkenness,
そしてガラテア5章が述べる—
and as Galatians chapter 5 says:
“things like these.”
“これに類するもの”を
捨て去る必要があります
Yes, they are to bring their lives
into accord with Bible principles.
そうです 自分の生き方を
聖書の原則に合わせるのです
Christians are to be
kind and considerate,
さらに 親切で 思いやりを示し—
mild-tempered and patient,
温和な気質と辛抱強さを培い
自制を働かせます
and are to exercise self-control.
They provide
and care for their own
自分の家族を養い
隣人を自分自身のように愛します
and love
their neighbor as themselves.
That’s a lot, isn’t it?
実に 多くのことが関係しています
It’s not a matter
of just glibly saying,
単に “わたしはクリスチャンです”
と言うだけのことではないのです
“I am a Christian.”
しかし これら数多くの
特徴がある中で—
But despite all of those
impressive characteristics
that we just enumerated,
真のクリスチャンを見分ける
主な特質について—
what did Jesus say
イエスは
何とおっしゃったでしょうか
the main identifying quality
皆さんの多くは
その答えをご存じでしょう
of a true Christian would be?
Most of you know the answer to that,
but let’s read it again
では 改めてヨハネ 13:34,35を
読んでみましょう
from John 13:34, 35.
こうあります
It says: “I am giving you
a new commandment,
“that you love one another;
just as I have loved you,
“you also love one another.
“By this all will know
that you are my disciples
—if you have love among yourselves.”
Those are the theme verses
これが
この話の主題となる聖句です
for my discussion
with you this month.
The topic is:
話の主題は
“愛—イエスの弟子を見分けるしるし” です
“Love—The Identifying Mark
of a Disciple of Jesus.”
Did you notice
in verse 34 that Jesus said
皆さんは イエスが34節の中で—
that he was giving them
at that time a “new commandment”?
“新しいおきて”を与えると
おっしゃったことにお気づきですか
But it sounds like
a very old commandment, doesn’t it?
でも実際には
古いおきてに聞こえるでしょう
Why, over 1,500 years
なぜなら イエスが
この言葉を語る1500年も前に—
before Jesus said
the words we just read,
モーセに与えられた律法の中にも—
the Law given to Moses said:
“あなたの仲間を自分自身のように
愛さねばならない”とあるからです
“You must love
your fellow man as yourself.”
レビ記 19:18の言葉です
—Leviticus 19:18.
So, what was “new”
about Jesus’ command
では ヨハネ 13章にあるイエスの
おきての どこが新しいのでしょうか
in John chapter 13?
He said that true Christians
were to love each other
イエスは 真のクリスチャンに—
“わたしがあなた方を愛した通りに”
互いを愛するようにとおっしゃいました
“just as I have loved you.”
ここが
モーセの律法と異なるところ—
That is what was different.
That was new,
新しいところです
not just love the other person
as you love yourself,
自分を愛するように
他の人を愛するだけでなく—
イエスが弟子たちを愛した通りに
愛するのです
but love him just like
Jesus loved His followers.
Well, what kind of love
would that be?
それはどんな種類の愛でしょうか
Self-sacrificing love
—and usually we think
自己犠牲的な愛です
イエスは わたしたちが
永遠の命の希望を持てるよう
of Jesus’ ultimate sacrifice,
his willingly giving his life
ご自分の命を差し出して
究極の犠牲を払われました
so that we might have the hope
of everlasting life.
But when you think about it,
that aspect of Jesus’ love
こうして
その自己犠牲の死は—
イエスの自己犠牲的な愛を
際立った仕方で示すものとなったのです
was exemplified
in a self-sacrificing death!
Now, it is true,
that as a Christian,
クリスチャンであるわたしたちにも—
仲間のために命を差し出す必要が
生じるかもしれません
we might at some time have to give
our life for a fellow Christian.
しかし いつもそうである
とは限りません
But we hope
it doesn’t come to that.
So instead of talking
about a self-sacrificing death,
それで 自己犠牲的な
死についてではなく—
we want to discuss
showing this new kind of love
自己犠牲的な
生き方によって—
この新しい愛を表わすことについて
考慮してみましょう
as evidenced
in a self-sacrificing life,
必ずしも死が伴うわけではないからです
not necessarily our death.
ご承知のとおり イエスの生涯と
三年半におよぶ宣教は—
You see, Jesus’ life
—his three-and-a-half-year ministry—
was a self-sacrificing life
of loving others.
人々への愛に根差した
自己犠牲的な生き方でした
In addition to doing good
それが求められたときに
良いことを行なうだけでなく—
when something requires it,
イエスの追随者は
率先して行動し—
a true follower of Jesus
霊的にも 他の面でも
人々を助けます
is to take
the initiative to help others
spiritually and otherwise.
他の人のために
積極的に行動します
He is to work actively
for their good.
The preaching and teaching
of the good news to others
良いたよりを人々に伝え
また教え—
—some of whom may even be hostile—
敵意を抱く人にさえ
そうすることは—
is one of the greatest expressions
of love, for it can result
愛の優れた表明といえます
それは永遠の命をもたらすからです
in everlasting life
to the recipients.
However,
according to Paul’s words
しかし テサロニケ第一2:8の
パウロの言葉によると—
at 1 Thessalonians 2:8,
a true Christian must
‘impart not only the good news of God
真のクリスチャンは—
“神の良いたよりだけでなく” —
but also his very self’
“自分の魂をさえ” —
良いたよりを受け入れる人に
分け与えます
in helping those who
accept the good news.
It’s that kind of love
そのような愛こそ イエスの語られた
弟子であることのしるしなのです
that Jesus said would be
an identifying mark of his disciples,
not specifically that his followers
ご自分の追随者すべてが
互いのために死ぬとではなく—
would all be dying for each other,
互いのために生きるべきである
と言われたのです
but more so that they
would all be living for each other.
そうです 毎日を生きる中で
互いに 自己犠牲的な愛を表わすのです
Yes, displaying self-sacrificing love
for one another
every day of their lives.
The four Gospels
are a treasure trove
四福音書には イエスの自己犠牲的な
愛の記録が詰まっています
of Jesus’ self-sacrificing love.
And yet,
they do not cover his actions
それでも キリストとして
過ごした日々の—
every day of his life
as the Christ.
すべての行動を収めている
わけではありません
His three-and-a-half-year ministry
イエスによる三年半の宣教は—
amounts to nearly
1,300 days of life and love.
1300日にも及ぶ
愛に満ちた日々でした
The written record
of Jesus’ life is admittedly brief,
イエスの人生の記録は
簡潔であるとはいえ—
but it is grand indeed!
確かに素晴らしいものです
しかし 毎日イエスを
その傍らで実際に見ることは—
However, the reality
of observing Jesus every day
must have been far grander
than what we have in print.
書き記したものより
はるかに素晴らしいでしょう
What we have in print
might be likened
わたしたちの手にある
書き記された記録は—
to a photo album
of Jesus’ life,
イエスの生涯中のスナップ写真を収めた
アルバムのようです
some snapshots.
By comparison,
what his apostles experienced
一方 使徒たちが 来る日も来る日も
イエスと共に過ごして経験したことは
with Jesus day after day
was like a continuous video
of his example of love.
その愛の手本を記録した
ビデオのようです
No wonder that,
at John 21:25,
使徒ヨハネが ヨハネ21:25で
次のように述べたのも 当を得ています
the apostle said:
“There are also . . .
“many other things that Jesus did,
“which if ever they were written
in full detail,
“I suppose the world itself
could not contain the scrolls written.”
ここで“ほかにも多くある”
と言われているのは—
It said there were
‘many other things Jesus did,’
イエスの言われた事ではなく
行なわれた事です
not many other things
that he said,
but that he did,
yes, deeds or acts
そうです その行ないによって
自己犠牲的な愛を表わされたのです
demonstrating
his self-sacrificing life of love!
わたしたちはすでに
宣べ伝える業こそ—
We already mentioned
the all-important preaching work
愛の 最も重要な表われ
であることを考えました
as being an act
of love on our part.
But how else
do we manifest
では 他にどんな方法で
クリスチャンの顕著な特徴といえる—
the most obvious trait
of a genuine Christian
—love like Jesus had?
イエスのような愛を
示せるのでしょうか
はじめに 会衆の長老たちについて
考えてみましょう
Let’s start by thinking
of the elders in the congregation.
At Philippians 2:17,
パウロは
フィリピ 2:17で—
会衆のために
自分を—
Paul said that he
had ‘poured himself out
“飲み物の捧げ物のように
注ぎだした”と述べています
to the congregation
like a drink offering.’
どのような意味でしょうか?
What did that mean?
これはフィリピの人々
を支えるためにー
It meant that he
drained himself out,
パウロが感情的にも 身体的にも
自分を費やし尽くしたという意味です
both physically and emotionally,
to support the Philippians.
Many of the elders
in our congregations
会衆の長老たちも
託された人々を世話するため—
have the same self-sacrificing love
同じような自己犠牲の愛を
示しています
for those under their care.
They give of their time
to shepherd
牧羊を行なったり
再調整を施すために時間を費やします
and readjust those in need.
They take the lead
in the ministry.
宣教奉仕に率先し—
深刻な健康上の問題や
不幸な出来事にも対応します
They respond when there is
a serious health issue or tragedy.
They pour themselves out for the friends,
thus identifying themselves
仲間のために自分を
費やし尽くすことにより—
キリストの弟子であることを
明らかにしています
as disciples of Christ.
But we do not have
to be an elder
しかし 仲間を励ますのに
長老である必要はありません
to provide a word
of encouragement, do we?
If we all keep focused
on others in the congregation,
わたしたちが 自分だけでなく
会衆の他の人にも目を向けているなら—
not just ourselves,
we will know
who needs to be bolstered
直面している状況や
試練のゆえに—
because of trials
or circumstances that they face.
支えを必要としている人がいる
ことに気付くでしょう
Giving in this way
is evidence of Christlike love.
このような面で与えることも
キリストのような愛の表われです
You may be thinking,
‘But I’m just a little old sister
中には “わたしは年寄りだから
他の人を励ますことなんてできない”
という人もいるでしょう
‘who finds it hard to squeeze out
a word of encouragement to others.’
でも 何かを言わなければ
ならないとは限りません
Perhaps you don’t have
to say anything,
just be there
集会や宣教に参加して
そこにいるだけでも—
at the meetings
or in the service.
周囲の人は あなたを見て
励みを受けます
When others see your face,
they are encouraged.
Follow along
as I read Acts 28:15.
使徒 28:15を
一緒に読んでみましょう
It reads:
“From there the brothers,
こうあります
“when they heard the news about us,
“came as far
as the Marketplace of Appius
“and Three Taverns to meet us.
“On catching sight of them,
“Paul thanked God
and took courage.”
パウロは 会いに来てくれた
兄弟たちを見ただけで—
Paul “took courage”
just by seeing the brothers
who came out to meet him.
“勇気づけられ”たのです
You encourage your brothers
皆さんの存在も
励ましとなります
and sisters by your presence.
Please follow along as I read
フィリピ 2:1-4も
読んでみましょう
Philippians 2:1-4.
パウロはここで “キリストにおける励まし”
という表現を用いこう述べています
Paul here describes it
as “encouragement in Christ.”
He says:
“If, then, there is
any encouragement in Christ,
“if any consolation of love,
“if any spiritual fellowship,
“if any tender affection
and compassion,
“make my joy full by being
“of the same mind
and having the same love,
“being completely united,
having the one thought in mind.
“Do nothing out of contentiousness
or out of egotism,
“but with humility
“consider others superior to you,
“as you look out not only
for your own interests,
but also for the interests of others.”
Did you notice
the self-sacrificing aspect
これらの愛や励ましが 自己犠牲的な
ものであることにお気づきでしょうか
of this love and encouragement?
そうです 彼は愛を抱くこと
について述べましたが—
Yes, he talked about having love,
but then he said,
“not . . . for your own interests,
but . . . for the interests of others.”
それは 自分の益ではなく
他の人の益のためのものです
That type of love
—in the interests of others—
他の人の益を図ろうとする
このような愛こそ—
is the identifying mark
of true Christians.
真のクリスチャンを見分ける
しるしであると言えます
What about visiting
the sick in your congregation
会衆内にいる 病気の人や
家を出られない人を—
or those who are housebound?
訪ねてみるのはどうですか
Sometimes these dear ones are
“out of sight, out of mind.”
これらの 愛する仲間たちが
忘れ去られてはなりません
We visit with those we see
when at the Kingdom Hall,
王国会館で会う仲間たちと
同じように—
家から出られない仲間のことも
気遣っているでしょうか
but do we think about those
who are shut-ins?
What was a major part
of Jesus’ loving acts when on earth?
イエスの愛ある業の中で
際立っていたのは何でしたか
There are numerous accounts
of Jesus and his apostles
数多くの記録が示すように
イエスと使徒たちは 病気を癒しました
healing the sick.
It’s true that we
cannot heal the sick,
わたしたちには
病気を癒す力はありませんが—
but it is in our power
to visit the sick.
病気の人を
訪問する力はあります
And what a healing
that is to their spirit!
それは人の内面を癒します
It means so much when
それらの人々のことを
集会での祈りに含めるだけでなく—
they are not just prayed for
at a meeting,
その祈りに調和して
個人的に訪ね—
but when those words of prayer
are backed up
行動によって愛を表わすことには
大きな意味があります
with an act of love
—a visit to them in person.
これこそ キリストのような
行動を伴う愛といえます
That is Christlike love in action.
Why not scroll down the list
of those in your service group
野外奉仕の群れの表を
見返してみて—
集会に来ていない仲間が
いないか確かめるのはどうでしょうか
with the thought in mind
of checking on those
who have been missing
from the meetings?
食事を必要としているでしょうか
Do they need a meal?
Do they need some help
家の周りのことで
助けを必要としているでしょうか
perhaps around the house?
医者に診てもらうために
交通手段が必要ですか
Do they need transportation
to the doctor?
Can we allow our love
to expand to fill their needs?
それらの必要を満たすために
愛を広げることができるでしょうか
Contributing to the worldwide work,
世界中の兄弟たちの必要を
顧みるために—
which cares for the needs
of our brothers around the world,
世界的な業に寄付することも
愛の表われであり—
is another act of love.
It demonstrates that we are
a true disciple of Christ.
キリストの真の弟子であることの
しるしです
この事に関連して 皆さんの多くは
自費で遠くの被災地に赴き—
Related to that, many of you have,
at your own expense,
traveled to far-flung places
自然災害後の再建を
援助してきました
to help rebuild
after a natural disaster has struck.
被災した人たちから寄せられる
数多くの反響は—
The overwhelming response
from the victims is evidence
皆さんが自己犠牲的な愛を
示しておられることの証拠です
of your self-sacrificing life
and love for your brothers.
It is hoped
that the reminder of Jesus
ヨハネ 13:34,35にある
諭しが—
at John 13:34, 35
will be good for all of us,
今月だけでなく生涯にわたって
皆さんの益となることを願っています
not just for this month,
but for our whole course of life.
世界人口の三分の一が
自分はクリスチャンであると唱えています
You know, about one third
of the world’s population
claims to be Christian.
しかし
その内のどれほどの人が—
But how many of them
show self-sacrificing love
自分の家族以外に“自己犠牲的な愛”を
示しているでしょうか？
outside of their immediate family?
Most are like a baseball team
in a uniform.
多くの人は ユニフォームを着た
野球選手のようです
They think having the word “Christian”
胸に “クリスチャン”という文字を派手に飾れば
それで十分だと考えているのです
emblazoned across the front
of their uniform
is all that is required.
しかし その大半は信徒席という
“ベンチ”に座っているだけで—
However, most of them
simply “sit on the bench,”
or on a pew in church,
試合に“出場”することもしません
and many do not even attend
“the game.”
彼らは クリスチャンの生き方を
していないのです
They do not live
the life of a Christian.
イエスは
ご自分の真の弟子になることには
Jesus made clear
that being a true disciple of his
“ユニフォームを着ること”—
is not merely
“wearing a uniform,”
つまり 追随者であると公言する以上の
ことが関係していることを示されました
simply claiming to be
his follower.
No, it involves
それには 行ないによって
積極的に愛を表わすこと
actively demonstrating
works of love,
いわばチームのために
“フルスイング”をして—
“swinging hard for the team,”
imitating the all-time greatest examples
of love,
愛の偉大な模範である—
エホバ神とイエス・キリストに
倣うことが関係しています
Jehovah God and his Son,
Jesus Christ.
パウロがコリント第二 8:8で
述べている通り—
As Paul said
at 2 Corinthians 8:8,
わたしたちは
“愛の純真さを試す”必要があります
we need “to test
the genuineness of [our] love.”
そうです
わたしたちは日々—
Yes, we need to daily prove
自分がイエスの真の弟子であることを
実証する必要があるのです
that we are
a genuine disciple of Jesus.
Brother Reinmueller will now
share some examples of how
さて ラインミュラー兄弟は—
これらの聖書の原則が 世界中の人々を
助けてきたことを示す—
the Bible principles
we just discussed
have helped people
around the world.
幾つかの実例を
紹介してくださいます
Alex.
Thank you, Brother Herd,
for that warm encouragement.
ハード兄弟
温かい励ましに感謝します
We’re more motivated than ever
エホバと人々への愛を実証するよう
心を動かされました
to prove our love for Jehovah and others.
We recently met Mamuka Tektumanashvili,
わたしたちは ジョージアの—
マムカ・テクトゥマナシュビリ兄弟
に会いました
from the country of Georgia.
He was a high-ranking officer
in the special forces there for many years.
彼は 長年にわたって
特殊部隊の高官でした
兄弟は
祖国を守ることが—
What made him realize
that defending his country
人生で得られる
最大の誉れではないことを—
is not the highest honor
a man can have in his life?
どのように理解したでしょうか？
経験をお聞きしましょう
This is his story.
わたしは18年間
大統領警護特別部隊の—
For 18 years
I served in a special unit
responsible
for presidential security.
任務に就いていました
This mission
demanded total self-sacrifice.
求められていたのは
全くの自己犠牲でした
For example,
the first and the last vehicles
大統領の護衛車両の
最前列と最後列はその部隊の車で—
of the presidential escort
belonged to this unit.
So if an attack
occurred on the president,
大統領への最初の攻撃は
わたしたちが受ける事になっていました
we were the first ones
to be hit with the fire.
For the last ten years
of service, I worked
最後の10年は
インストラクターとして—
as an instructor
and trained new staff
新しいスタッフが
大統領の警護に就けるよう訓練しました
to provide
presidential security in the future.
Those working in this field
must be fearless.
この任務のためには
恐れ知らずのプロでなければならないと—
They must be professionals,
次の世代に教えたものです
and that is what I taught
to succeeding generations.
I just loved my job.
わたしは仕事を愛しておりー
I was a fervent patriot.
熱烈な愛国主義者でした
I had a special regard
for the flag of my country.
国旗に特別の敬意を持ちー
いつもバッグの中に
武器とともに入れていました
In one bag,
I always had weapons and the flag.
わたしの中の愛国心は根深くー
Patriotism
was so deep-rooted in me
that I would beat up a person
国籍が違うというだけで
その人を叩きのめすほどでした
simply because he was
of another nationality.
神は わたしのような者が近づくのを
許すはずがないと思っていました
I always thought
that God would never allow
people like me
to draw close to him.
ある日エホバの証人が来て
妻とわたしに証言をしました
One day, Jehovah’s Witnesses came
and preached to my wife and me.
わたしたちは真理にひかれ
妻はぜひ聖書研究がしたいと言いました
We were so interested
in the truth that my wife
even expressed
a desire to study the Bible.
Because there were rumors
circulating about Jehovah’s Witnesses,
エホバの証人についての
噂があったのでー
まず集会で
すべてが適切だと確認できたら—
I decided first to make sure that everything
was decent at their meetings
妻が関わることを許可しよう
と決めていました
and only then allow my wife
to associate with them.
集会後
わたしは感動していました
After the meeting,
I was absolutely thrilled.
Everyone was well-mannered,
with friendly, smiling faces.
皆が笑顔で礼儀正しく
フレンドリーです
I realized that there was nothing there
to threaten my wife’s well-being.
妻の福祉を脅かすものなどない
彼らとの交友は有益だと分かりました
On the contrary, their association
would be beneficial for her.
間もなく妻と長女は
バプテスマを受けました
Soon my wife
and our eldest daughter got baptized.
As for me, I enjoyed associating
with Jehovah’s Witnesses.
わたしは証人たちとの交友を
楽しんでおりー
後に聖書研究も始めました
Later, I also started
to study the Bible.
生活を全く変化させなければならない
と分かっていましたがー
I knew that I had to make
drastic changes in my life,
but my job
prevented me from doing so.
仕事が妨げになっていました
Moreover, I felt
that door-to-door preaching
わたしにとって 家から家の宣教は
戦闘よりはるかに難しく感じられー
was far more difficult
than engaging in combat.
I respected Jehovah’s Witnesses
for their courage and strength.
エホバの証人の勇気と強さを
尊敬していました
わたしは少しづつ良い変化を
遂げていました
Little by little,
I too was changing for the better.
I wanted to quit my job and inform
my colleagues about my religious beliefs.
仕事を辞めたい—
同僚にわたしの信条を知らせたい
と思うようになり—
最近学んだ聖句を全部書き出し
オフィスの壁にピンで貼りました
So I wrote down all the Bible verses
I had recently learned
and then pinned them
on the wall in my office.
I also started to think
about how to make a living
仕事を辞めた後に
生計を立てるため—
after leaving my job
and decided to learn a trade.
技術を学ぶことにしました
I started to buy tools
in order to be ready
家族を養うための道具を
揃え始めました
to take care of my family.
決断の時が来たと思いました
I realized that the time
had come to make a decision.
The day I quit my job
辞職した日は
人生で最も幸福な日の一つとなりました
was one of the happiest days
of my life.
その日からわたしの人生すべてを
清い良心でエホバに捧げています
Since then, I’ve been able
to dedicate every minute of my life
to Jehovah
with a clean conscience.
In a few months, I got baptized.
数ヶ月でバプテスマを受けました
In the beginning,
we were hardly making a living.
初めは生計を立てるのが大変でしたが—
However, this taught me
to trust in Jehovah.
エホバを信頼することを学べました
I tried my best to keep
service to Jehovah in first place.
エホバへの奉仕を
いつも第一にしてきました
I deeply appreciate
the support of my brothers
兄弟姉妹たちとの交友や支えに
心から感謝しています
and sisters
and association with them.
以前は人からの命令に
時には渋々従っていましたが—
Before, I used to carry out
the orders of men
—some of which
I carried out reluctantly.
今は “ここにわたしがおります！
わたしを遣わしてください！”と述べた—
But now I am happy to carry out
an assignment from Jehovah
with the same spirit
that the prophet Isaiah had,
who said:
イザヤと同じ精神で—
“Here I am! Send me!”
喜んでエホバからの割当を
果たしています
As a family, we decided to move
where the need was greater,
家族で必要の大きな所での
奉仕のために移動し—
and this has united
our family even more.
絆がより強くなった
と感じています
This is the bag
武器を入れていたバッグの中身は—
in which
I always carried weapons,
but now they are replaced
with a Bible and Bible literature.
聖書と文書に変わりました
In the past, I thought
家から家の宣教は絶対にできない
と思っていましたが—
I could never preach
from door to door.
But now I can say with conviction
“神にとってはすべてのことが
可能です” と—
that the words of Jesus
have proved true in my case:
“All things are possible with God.”
確信を込めて言うことができます
テクトゥマナシュビリ兄弟は
現在 長老として—
Brother Tektumanashvili
now serves as an elder,
and he has also been
a regular pioneer since 2014.
さらに 2014年からは
正規開拓者として奉仕しています
While Brother Tektumanashvili
served the government for many years,
長年 政府で働いてきた
兄弟とは対照的に—
犯罪に関わってきた人々もいます
there are those who live
on the other side of the law.
偏見のない エホバの愛は
彼らにも達してきたでしょうか
How does Jehovah’s unprejudiced love
reach out to them?
ご一緒に アフリカの
コンゴ民主共和国を訪れてみましょう
Join us as we travel
to the Democratic Republic of Congo
in Africa,
兄弟たちは
特別な努力を払い—
where our brothers make
special efforts to reach people
普段 家から家の奉仕で見出せない
人々を訪問しています
we would not normally
find from door to door.
I could say that my past
was really an unhappy past.
わたしの過去は本当に不幸なものでした
I went through very difficult times
during my childhood.
子ども時代にとてもつらい経験をし—
I lost hope
より良い生活への希望を失いました
that I could ever have
a better life.
Because of that,
そのため 悪い仲間と
付き合うようになり—
I started to associate
with the wrong people in my life.
One night, I was arrested
and sent to Buluo Prison.
ある晩 逮捕されて
ブルオ刑務所に送られました
It is a high-security prison
in Congo.
コンゴでも
警備の厳重な刑務所です
刑務所はとても危険な所ですが—
Prison is a very dangerous place.
彼らがすんなりと真理を
受け入れるのに驚きました
But I was surprised how they
accepted the truth so easily.
Really, I was amazed.
本当にびっくりしました
We needed to obtain permission
刑務所で引き続き宣べ伝えられるように
許可をもらう必要がありました
to be able to continue
to preach in the prison.
We had so enjoyed
the preaching work there.
そこでの宣教をとても楽しんでいました
I went to see the authorities in the city
to find out what was required
わたしは市の当局に行き—
刑務所で宣べ伝える許可を
どうしたらもらえるか尋ねました
so that we could have permission
to preach in the prison.
To my great amazement,
they simply handed me a paper
驚いたことに
彼らはただ紙を渡して—
要請を書面にするように言いました
and told me to put
my request in writing.
それから 待つように言われ—
They asked me to wait.
数分もしないうちに
わたしは許可証を手にしていました
Within minutes,
I had the authorization
in my hands
without paying anything at all.
何も払わずにです
Every time the situation
自分たちではとうてい乗り越えられない
不可能に思える状況でも—
seemed insurmountable to us,
impossible to us,
エホバはふさわしい解決策を差し伸べて
いつも助けてくださいました
we saw the hand of Jehovah
providing us
with the suitable solution.
当局により この特別な証言の分野に
大きな弾みがつきました
The authorization gave a great boost
to this special witnessing initiative.
コリント第一 9:22, 23
にあるように—
In harmony with 1 Corinthians 9:22, 23,
the brothers could then
‘become all things to people of all sorts,
兄弟たちは“あらゆる人に対して
あらゆるものとなる”ことができました
so that they might
by all possible means save some.’
“何とかして幾人かでも救うためです”
Some religious leaders
who were also prisoners
収容されている
宗教指導者の幾人かは—
were extremely opposed
to our presence.
わたしたちのことで
ものすごく反対し—
They conspired and had us
thrown out of our meeting place.
共謀して わたしたちを
集会所から追い出しました
The prisoners themselves
were concerned about this.
囚人たちはこれを憂慮し—
前のより もっと広い集会所を
見つけました
They found another meeting place
even more spacious than the former.
ブルオは会衆から
８キロの所にあるので—
Since Buluo is eight kilometers
away from our congregation,
宣教と集会に参加する
兄弟姉妹のために—
to transport the group who support
the preaching work and meetings,
長老団は毎週土曜日にブルオに行く
ミニバスを２台手配しました
the body of elders organized two minibuses
to go out every Saturday to Buluo.
到着すると 兄弟姉妹は
８時半に宣教を始め—
Once they arrive,
they begin the preaching work at 8:30,
and at 10 o’clock
the meetings start.
10時に集会が始まります
週の集会はすべて土曜日に開かれます
All the meetings of the week
are held on the Saturday.
エホバの証人にはとても感心しています
Concerning Jehovah’s Witnesses,
personally, I am very impressed.
証人たちが受刑者を本格的に
助けるようになって3年余りになります
It’s more than three years they’ve been
more active in helping the detainees.
The reeducation of the prisoners
is assured by Jehovah’s Witnesses.
囚人の再教育は
エホバの証人によって保証されています
This is a good collaboration
on the part of Jehovah’s Witnesses.
エホバの証人の良い協力のおかげです
とても感謝しています
With this I’m very happy.
2014年12月の巡回大会に
175人が出席しました
One hundred
and seventy-five attended
the circuit assembly
in December 2014,
which was held in the prison,
and seven were baptized.
この大会は刑務所で開かれ—
7人がバプテスマを受け—
Local media covered the event.
地元のメディアでも取り上げられました
ここブルオ刑務所でエホバの証人が
バプテスマを受けるのを初めて見ました
This is the first time I have seen
Jehovah’s Witnesses
baptized here
in the Buluo Prison.
とても良いことです
This is a good thing.
このような支援を今後も続けて
いってほしいと思います
I encourage you
to continue with this assistance.
Every week there are
more than 80 in attendance
毎週80人以上が出席します
それより多く
140人のこともあります
and sometimes
more than that, even 140.
うち36人が伝道者で—
In the attendance
there are the 36 publishers
ブルオ刑務所で真理を学びました
—the brothers who learned
the truth in Buluo Prison—
30人がバプテスマを受けた兄弟で—
30 are baptized
and 6 unbaptized.
6人がバプテスマを受けていない
伝道者です
I visited many churches
because I had a lot of questions,
多くの教会を訪ねました
たくさんの疑問があったからです
but I never got
any exact answers.
でも 確かな答えは得られませんでした
When I went to see
Jehovah’s Witnesses,
エホバの証人に会いに行った時—
聖書から正確な答えを
示してもらいました
they gave me accurate answers
from the Bible.
To know that Jehovah
is compassionate
エホバが同情心に富み
進んで許してくださることを知って—
and ready to forgive,
these are the qualities
that touched me.
心を打たれました
I used to be a soldier.
わたしは かつて兵士で—
I was in the military.
軍部にいました
いろいろな教会に行きました
I attended various churches
とても気にかかる疑問があったからです
because I had a question
that bothered me a lot.
悪いことが人々に絶えず降りかかるのを
神はなぜ許しておられるのだろうって
I wondered why God allows
bad things to happen
to people all the time.
While I was in prison,
刑務所にいる時に
エホバの証人が訪ねて来ました
Jehovah’s Witnesses came to visit
and talk to us.
わたしは証人たちに—
I asked them
the same question,
“なぜ神は病気や苦しみが続くのを
許されるのですか？”と—
“Why does God allow sickness
and suffering to continue?”
同じ質問をしました
They replied by using
three Bible verses.
証人たちは3つの聖句を使って
答えてくれました
I was very happy because I received
the answer to my question.
答えが得られてとても幸せでした
Papy Okito is a brother
パピー・オキト兄弟は刑務所で
真理を学びました
who learned
the truth in prison.
He made
such remarkable progress
目覚ましい進歩を遂げ—
今では看守たちの信用を得ています
that those in charge
now have confidence in him.
Like Joseph in the Bible,
聖書中のヨセフのように—
he has been placed in a position
of supervision over the other prisoners.
他の囚人を監督する立場にいます
さらに進歩したため—
He also made further progress,
and thus, the management has requested
管理局は彼の刑期を短くする
ように要請しました
that his prison sentence
be reduced.
刑務所に着いた時
希望を失っていました
When I arrived in the prison,
I had lost hope.
I thought for me
it was the end.
もう終わりだと思いました
By means of the Bible,
聖書のおかげで 人生に
喜びと希望を見いだしました
I have found joy
and hope in my life.
That is why today I am happy
even though I am still here.
だからこそ
まだここにいても幸せです
楽園はわたしのためにも
あるのですから！
But I know
that the Paradise is for me.
It’s been five years
since the brothers
ブルオ刑務所での証言が
始まって 5年になります
started preaching
in the Buluo Prison.
一つの週末に 500冊以上の
雑誌を配布することもあります
At times, the publishers place
up to 500 magazines in one weekend.
配布数だけが 宣教における
成功の尺度ではありませんが—
Although our success is not
measured by the number of placements,
刑務所の人々が 霊的な渇きを
覚えていることは明らかです
this response does paint
a clear picture
of the spiritual thirst
among these prisoners.
ここ数か月の間に—
In the last few months,
inside these prison walls,
この刑務所にいる11名の方々が—
11 more unbaptized publishers
have been approved.
バプテスマを受けていない
伝道者になりました
What a loving act by Jehovah
and his organization
エホバとその組織による
愛ある業により—
それらの人々の霊的な必要が
満たされてきたのです
to help such individuals satisfy
their spiritual needs!
In the late 1950’s,
さて 1950年代後半—
the opposition
against Jehovah’s Witnesses
旧ソビエト連邦で生じた
エホバの証人に対する反対により—
in the former Soviet Union
resulted in homes being searched,
brothers being followed,
家宅捜査が行われ
兄弟たちは尾行されました
and many of our brothers
and sisters being sent
そして 多くの兄弟姉妹が シベリア
などの強制収容所に送られました
to Communist concentration camps
in Siberia,
among other places.
1956年と57年には—
In 1956 and 1957,
世界中の大会に出席した
462,000人以上の代表者が—
over 462,000
convention delegates worldwide
満場一致で請願書に同意しました
unanimously adopted a petition
そこには 証人たちが耐え忍んでいる
扱いが書かれており—
which clearly outlined the treatment
Jehovah’s Witnesses were enduring.
ソビエトの当局者に
送られました
It was sent
to the Soviet authorities,
しかし 大きな変化は
見られませんでした
but sadly, not much changed.
1958年—
The next year,
at the 1958 international convention
ニューヨーク市ヤンキースタジアムで
国際大会が開かれ—
at Yankee Stadium
in New York,
“鉄のカーテンの背後で”と題する
話がなされました
a talk was given entitled
“Behind the Iron Curtain.”
During the talk,
delegates were surprised
その話の中で—
ソ連の兄弟姉妹からの録音された
あいさつと歌が流され—
when a recording of greetings
and songs from brothers
and sisters in the Soviet Union
was played.
聴衆を驚かせました
Despite the risk of losing
their freedom,
兄弟たちは自分たちの自由を失う
危険に面しながら—
the brothers produced
and sent these recordings.
それを準備したのです
Well, a few months ago,
数か月前のことですが—
some of those who were involved
in making the recording
その録音に携わった兄弟たちの幾人かが
初めてそれを聞く機会がありました
were able to listen to it
for the first time
Several of them
found out only then
中には ヤンキースタジアムでの
大会でそれが流されたことを—
that the recording had been played
at the convention at Yankee Stadium.
初めて知った人もいました
わたしたちも その場に同席しました
Our team was present
at that gathering.
The brothers told us
to prepare songs for a recording.
録音するための歌を準備するように
言われました
When we were singing,
I never imagined
まさか大会のためだとは
夢にも思っていませんでした
that it was for a convention,
because I did not know about that.
知らなかったんです
We sang as usual.
ただ普通に歌っていました
The chorus was made up
of about 20 persons,
コーラス隊は大体20人で—
バラックのような建物の一室で
録音が行われました
and the recording
was made in a room
in a barrack-like building.
I just looked after the chorus
to give them the right tone.
皆が正しい音程で歌えるように
指揮しました
If someone sang a little off-key,
she would right away remark:
誰かの音が外れていると
姉妹はすぐに気づいて—
“Altos, you are off!”
or “Tenor, you are off!”
“アルト 外れていますよ”—
“テナー 外れています”などと
言ってくれたので—
so that there would be no slips,
no mistakes.
音程をきちんと合わせられました
録音中は気を付けなければ
なりませんでした
We had to be very careful
when we were recording.
And so we knew not to talk.
このことについては
誰にも話してはなりませんでした
I could not tell
anyone about it.
It was secret
—absolutely secret.
極秘でした
良いイントネーションで—
They chose a brother
who spoke very good Russian,
きれいなロシア語を話せる—
who had good intonation,
and who had a good voice.
声のいい兄弟が選ばれました
And as I recall, we made
the recording on our first attempt.
私の記憶では
一回で録音できました
Brother Yuriy Dobychin
said the greetings.
ユーリー・ダビチ兄弟が
あいさつを述べました
私は若く 良い声に恵まれていました
I was young then,
and I had a good voice.
So I had to say
the greetings
それで ヤンキースタジアムに
集まっている兄弟たちに—
from the brothers
in the Soviet Union
ソ連の兄弟たちを代表して—
あいさつを述べることになりました
for the brothers gathered
at Yankee Stadium.
私たちも 新しい世の社会と
歩調を合わせたいと
強く願っています
As the brothers who made
the recording told me,
録音を行なった兄弟たちが
話してくれたことですが—
the most difficult assignment
for them
録音したものを
国外へ持ち出すのが—
was how to get this recording
across the border.
一番大変でした
The brothers cut it up
into pieces
兄弟たちはそれを切り分け—
and sewed it
into the lining of a jacket
ジャケットの裏側に縫い付けました
because that’s how
confidential letters were sent.
そのようにして—
内密の手紙を送っていたのです
One married couple
from Poland,
ポーランドから休暇で
ロシアに来ていた夫婦が—
who were vacationing
in Russia,
それをソ連から運びだすのを
引き受けてくれました
agreed to take it
back with them
—to take it
out of the Soviet Union.
And that’s where they ran
into serious problems.
その後 彼らは
問題に巻き込まれます
From Brother Scheider’s letter,
ポーランドで録音を受け取った
シャイダー兄弟の手紙です
who received
the audio recording in Poland:
‟当局が兄弟を別にしました”
“The security officers separated
our brother from the others.
“捜査員が「持っているフィルムと
3通の手紙を渡すように」と言いました”
“Then an officer said to him:
‘Please give us the film
and the three letters you have with you.’
“The brother saw now,
of course,
“兄弟は どこかに裏切り者が
いたことを悟りました”
“that there had been
a traitor somewhere.
“He and his wife
were now thoroughly searched.
“2人は厳しく取り調べられました”
“Every square centimeter
of their cases
“持っていたカバンと中身は
隅から隅まで調べられました”
“was carefully examined
together with their contents.
“それから服をすべて
脱がされました”
“Then both were stripped naked.
“取り調べ中「どこに隠したか？誰に渡したか？
さっさと言え！」と怒鳴られました”
“While this was going on,
they yelled at the brother:
‘Tell us where you have hidden everything
or to whom you have given it!’
“They were absolutely convinced
that he had everything with him.
“兄弟が絶対に持っていると
確信していたのです”
“Several times they took him
to the office
“数回にわたり—”
“兄弟を国境警察と
公安警察に連れて行き—”
“of the frontier police
and to the security police,
“何度も取り調べ
ひどく脅しました”
“searching him
again and again
“and being terribly angry.
“でも最後には根負けしました”
“But they finally had to give up.
“They kept him back
for 24 hours
“兄弟は24時間拘留され—”
“and questioned him
in the presence of ten specialists.
“10人の専門家の前で
尋問されました”
But he came out victorious.”
“しかし 妥協しませんでした”
Sadly, even the brothers
残念ながら—
この件にかかわった兄弟たちでさえ—
who were involved
don’t know who this couple
テープをポーランドに運んでくれた
この夫婦のことを知りません
who brought the tape
into Poland was.
さて 驚くべきことに—
ロシアの兄弟たちから—
この大会にメッセージが届いています!
それでは、メッセージの一部を—
ロシア語でお聞かせしましょう
愛する兄弟姉妹たち：
天の父の大いなる憐れみにより—
今日エホバの証人の
国際大会に出席している皆さんに—
ここロシアでの生活と活動について—
短いメッセージをお送りしたいと思います
至高者であるエホバのおかげで—
ここで生活し 働いています
第二次世界大戦後から今日に至るまで—
この古い世で 信仰と忠誠を守るための戦いは—
厳しく過酷なものとなっています
しかしこうした困難や逮捕—
迫害や弾圧の中でも—
私たちは喜びにあふれています
多くの善意の人々が真理を知り—
良き牧者であるイエスの—
指導の下に来るのを見るのは—
大きな喜びです
本当にうれしいことです
Well, for me it was, of course, a great joy,
since the goal was reached after all.
こうやって成し遂げられたのですから
Everything was so wonderful
at that time.
あの時 すべてが素晴らしかったのです
I really enjoyed it all!
本当に楽しかったです
Nothing could describe
the joy I felt.
あの喜びは言い表せません
I was overwhelmed with feelings.
心の底から 本当に感動しました
And so my voice was recorded,
and the greetings were heard
こうして 私の声は録音され—
in New York
at Yankee Stadium.
ニューヨークのヤンキースタジアムで—
流されたのです
These dear brothers and sisters
have no regrets.
これらの兄弟姉妹は
少しも後悔していません
They are happy
that their efforts encouraged
自分たちの努力が 当時も今も—
so many thousands
back then and today.
仲間の励みとなっていることを
喜んでいます
The kind of love
these brothers and sisters showed
兄弟姉妹が示したような愛は—
is often noticed
by those not in the truth.
しばしば 真理にいない人の
目にも留まります
米国の若い夫婦
ジェレマイア・ドレイパーと妻のホリーは—
A young couple from the United States,
Jeremiah and Holly Draper,
まさに そのことを経験しました
experienced just that.
The blessings that I enjoy today
今 数え切れないくらいの
祝福を味わっています
are so numerous.
I have a true inner sense
本当に深い喜びや
幸福感があります
of joy and happiness.
I can’t help
but be appreciative,
感謝せずにはいられません
すべてエホバのおかげです
so grateful
for all that Jehovah does.
But it wasn’t
always this way for us.
でも 最初からこうだったわけでは
ありません
暗い家庭で育ち—
It was a dark world growing up.
子どもらしい生活はありませんでした
I never knew
what being a child was like.
自分はどんな大人になるかと思うと
怖くなりました
I was afraid
of who I would grow up to be.
I felt like I had no choice.
選択肢はないように思えたので—
Then at a very young age,
I, as well,
若くして 自分も周りと同じような
生き方を始めました
started to partake
of what I saw going on around me.
I learned quickly that it helped numb
それが 自分の感情を麻痺させる
助けになることにすぐ気付きました
the feelings that I had.
Drugs were a way
to escape that.
ドラッグはそうした感情から
抜け出す一手段でした
I was in a lot of trouble
with the law.
法律を何度も犯しました
I knew I needed change,
変わらなければならないことは分かって
いたので若くして軍隊に入りました
so I joined the military
at a young age.
Around my teenage years,
my life became difficult.
十代のころ問題を
抱えるようになりました
ドラッグやアルコールにおぼれ
自滅的な生活をしましたが—
I started to turn to drugs and alcohol
and self-destructive ways,
but none of these things
were making me happy.
幸福にはなれませんでした
I was very lonely.
とても孤独でした
わたしのことなど誰も気に留めず
知ろうともしません
No one knew me;
no one cared to know me.
I felt so lost,
自分を見失い
心の大きな穴を埋めようと—
and I was trying
to fill this big hole in my heart
いろいろなことに手を出したものの
どれもだめでした
with so many things,
and none of it worked.
結局ドラッグとアルコールのせいで
起こした交通事故のため—
One of my many car accidents,
due to drugs and alcohol,
刑務所に入りました
ended me up in jail
for 30 days straight.
30日間でした
I felt like a hopeless mess.
どん底を味わいました
I just knew
something’s got to change.
何かを変えなければと思いました
So I joined the military,
それで自分に必要な大変化を期待して
軍隊に入りましたが—
thinking it was going to be
the positive great change
that I needed,
うまくいきませんでした
but it was not.
I remember
joining the military
わたしは人生に重みが加わると思って
軍隊に入りましたが—
hoping that it
would bring some sort
of authority into my life,
再び怒りとアルコールとドラッグの
生活にはまり込んでいきました
but I again started
to spiral
into my anger,
my alcohol and drug abuse.
わたしは軍隊から出されることに
なりましたが—
The military decided
to let me out.
But during deployment
is where I met Holly.
軍隊が展開している期間中に
ホリーと出会いました
Holly also got
out of the military,
ホリーも軍隊を出ることになって
いたので 一緒に生活を始めました
and we started
to live a life together.
But we were still searching
for something to fill
でも二人は人生で感じていた空虚感を
満たしてくれるものをまだ模索していました
the emptiness
that we both felt in our lives.
ジェレマイアとわたしはモンタナの
鉄工所で一緒に働いていました
Jeremiah and I were both working
in a steel factory in Montana.
During this time,
I was being trained on a drill
この間 わたしはモリーという名の
エホバの証人の姉妹から—
by one of Jehovah’s Witnesses,
a sister named Molly.
穴あけ機の訓練を受けていました
モリーは“この機械は2時間くらい
止まるので—”
Molly said, “You’re
going to have down time
“on this machine,
maybe a couple of hours,
“工具箱の中の物を何でも自由に
読んでいいわよ” と言いました
so feel free to read
whatever I have in my tool box.”
I opened it
箱を開けるとすぐ「聖書は実際に
何を教えていますか」という—
and immediately
a little yellow book,
What Does the Bible Really Teach?,
caught my eye.
小さな黄色の本が
目に留まりました
I loved the pictures.
挿絵や最初に出ていた聖句が
気に入りすぐに心が引かれました
The scriptures
at the beginning of the book,
they touched my heart immediately,
and I felt like,
“ずっと探していた質問の答えが
ここにあるんだわ” と感じました
‘These answer all the questions
I’ve been searching
for my entire life!’
コリーという名のもう一人の姉妹が
やって来てこう言いました
Another sister came over,
her name was Cory,
“モリーとわたしは明日 聖書について
あなたとお話しできるわ—”
and she said:
“Molly and I can come over,
“and we can talk to you
about the Bible tomorrow.
“質問があれば聖書から
お答えしたいと思うの”
If you have any questions,
we’d love to answer them using the Bible.”
わたしは “ええ 是非” と
答えました
I said, “Yes, come over!”
わたしは少し懸念を抱いていました
I was a little bit
more apprehensive.
I stayed just to make sure
nothing got weird,
厄介なことにならないよう
慎重に構えていましたが—
but this was finally
でもその心配は全くありませんでした
something very different.
話されることは聖書に基づいていました
And I realized what they were saying
came from the Bible.
そういう経験は初めてでした
I’d never seen that before.
わたしたちは王国会館に招待されました
They invited us
to the Kingdom Hall.
We went in,
everybody had their Bible,
中に入ると皆が聖書を持ち
一緒に聖書を調べていました
had time to look
the scriptures up together,
そして皆 温かい人たちで
歓迎してくれました
and everybody was
so warm and inviting.
わたしたちがずっと探し求めていた
人々がそこにいたのです
These were the people
I’d been searching for my entire life.
ついに変化できるようになりました
All of a sudden change
was possible.
どんな変化をすべきかは
分かっていました
We knew what changes
we needed to make in our life.
それまでしてきたことや活動など—
What we were doing,
our actions,
エホバが憎まれることを
やめることが必要でした
we had to clear out things
that Jehovah hates.
家中を歩き回って処分すべき
ものを探し回るかのようでした
Like just going through
our house and deciding
what it is
that we need to get rid of.
By allowing the truth
to transform our lives,
真理が生活を変革する
ようにした結果—
Holly and I’ve received
many blessings,
多くの祝福を受け ベテルで
奉仕できるようになりました
and eventually we were able
to come here together and serve at Bethel.
わたしたちは溶接所で
真理を知りましたが—
We got the truth in a weld shop,
今ではエホバの家でエホバのために
溶接の仕事をしています
and now I get to weld
here in Jehovah’s house for him.
わたしは給水装置 冷蔵庫
クーラーなどの—
I perform maintenance
on water fountains,
refrigerators, coolers.
メンテナンスを行なっています
共に働く兄弟姉妹から
訓練を受けながら—
Being trained by the brothers
and sisters I work with
クリスチャン人格を精錬する上での
助けを得ています
just helps me to refine
my Christian personality.
エホバが天からご覧になり
わたしたちのよくない点すべてを—
It’s so nice to know
that Jehovah
is looking down on us;
見ておられることを知るのは
良いことです
that he was able
to see through
何かを見出したなら—
all of the trash
that was there in our life.
それについて行動することも
おできになります
He was able to find something
わたしは詩編 145:19について
よく考えます
and decided to work with it.
And I really think of a scripture,
Psalm 145:19:
“神はご自分を恐れる者たちの願いを
遂げてくださり—”
“He satisfies the desire
of those
“助けを求めるその叫びを聞き
彼らを救ってくださいます”
“who fear him;
he hears their [cry] for help,
エホバはそうしてくださいました
and [he] rescues them.”
Jehovah did that for us.
エホバにみ手を働かせて
くださるよう願い求めるなら
If you ask Jehovah
to display his hand in your life,
エホバは疑いなく
そうしてくださることを確信できます
no doubt at all in my mind,
that will happen.
Did you notice how
Jeremiah and Holly were touched
ジェレマイアとホリーが
初めて王国会館を訪れたとき—
by the Christian love shown to them
どのようにクリスチャン愛に
心を打たれたでしょうか？
when they visited
the Kingdom Hall for the first time?
ジェレマイアは 皆が温かく歓迎し
招き入れてくれたと述べています
Jeremiah said that everybody
was so warm and inviting.
Yes, love truly is
確かに愛は イエスの弟子を
見分けるしるしです
the identifying mark of Jesus’ disciples.
But Jesus taught that love
for fellow believers and our neighbor
しかしイエスは 仲間や
他の人々への愛は—
is second to our love for Jehovah.
神への愛に次ぐものであると
教えました
Being kind and encouraging to others
他の人に親切を示し
励ますとしても—
is of little value if it’s not rooted
神を喜ばせたいという
強い願いに基づいていないなら—
in a deep desire
to please our heavenly Father.
あまり価値がありません
In the following dramatization,
続くドラマでは—
ある若い兄弟が 心を注意深く吟味
することの大切さに気付かされます
a young brother is reminded of the value
of carefully examining his heart.
ショーン といいます
My name is Shawn.
I was raised in the truth.
真理のうちに育てられました
見かけは よくやっているように
見えたと思います
I was doing everything right.
でも本当は
間違ったことをしていました
But I was doing everything wrong.
I was in my senior year of high school.
高校3年の時のことです
Everything was going great
すべてが順調でした
until this new girl joined our school.
転校してきた彼女に会うまでは……
どうしてこうなったのか
わからないんです
I really don’t know
how it even started.
We just sort of hit it off
and became good friends.
ただ すごく気が合って
すぐに仲良くなりました
すごく話しやすい子だったんです
I mean, she was so easy to talk to.
Before I knew it,
気がつくと ずっとメールしていました
we were texting all the time.
Then, one thing led to another.
それが始まりで……
お互いに触れるようになっても
まだなんとかなると思っていましたが—
Honestly, when things
started to get physical,
I thought I could control it,
実際は
もう止められなくなっていました
but it was only getting worse.
I didn’t want to let my parents down.
親を悲しませたくない—
So I started lying to them,
そんな気持ちで親に—
そして自分に嘘をつくようになりました
and then I started lying to myself.
集会に行って
割り当てを果たしてさえいれば—
I thought if I could just keep
going to the meetings and do my parts,
大丈夫だと考えていたんです
it could somehow be OK.
全然 大丈夫ではありませんでした
But I was far from OK.
翌日の晩 家族の崇拝で—
The next night, we had family worship.
アナニアと
その妻サッピラの記述を読みました
We were reading about the account
of Ananias and his wife, Sapphira.
困窮した仲間のために
基金が設けられたとき—
When a special fund was set up
for needy Christians, Ananias sold a field.
アナニアは畑を売り—
But then, he boldly claimed
he was contributing
ずうずうしくも
その代金の全額を寄付したと言いました
the entire proceeds of its sale.
でも実際には—
In reality, though,
Ananias had “secretly held back
自分のために“代価の幾らかを
ひそかに取ってお”いたのです
some of the price”
for his personal gain.
ペテロは大胆に言いました
Peter boldly said to him:
“You have lied,
“あなたは 人にではなく
神に対して虚偽の振る舞いをした”
not to men, but to God.”
エホバはその虚偽にだまされなかった
Jehovah wasn’t fooled
by their pretense.
詩編 44:21にはこうありました—
Then we read Psalm 44:21:
“[God] is aware
“神は心の秘密を知っておられる”
of the secrets of the heart.”
アナニアとサッピラの記述を読んで
気づきました
Reading this account of Ananias
and Sapphira made me realize
僕は ただ親や友達に
嘘をついていたんじゃない
I wasn’t just lying
to my parents or my friends.
エホバに嘘をついていた
I was lying to Jehovah.
両親をがっかりさせること以上に—
As much as I didn’t want
to let my parents down,
even more so,
I didn’t want to let Jehovah down.
エホバを悲しませたくありませんでした
その晩 ひたすら祈りました
I prayed long that night.
包み隠さず すべてお伝えし—
I didn’t hold anything back.
朝になるころには 心を決めていました
By the next morning,
I knew what I wanted to do.
簡単ではありませんでしたが
両親は本当によく支えてくれ—
It wasn’t easy,
but my parents were very supportive,
and I also got the help
I needed from the elders.
長老から必要な助けも受けました
何年か経った今だから言えますが—
It’s been a few years,
but as I look back now,
以前の僕は
裏表の生活をする若者でした
I was one of those kids
living a double life.
でも エホバに助けていただき—
But now with Jehovah’s help,
今 最高の生き方をしています
I’m living the best life.
What a clear warning this is,
非常に明快な諭しでした
not only for young ones
but also for those of us
若い人だけでなく 長年エホバに
仕えてきた人にも必要な諭しです
who have served Jehovah
for many, many years.
わたしたちが良く知っているとおり
幾十年もエホバに仕えてきたとしても—
As we well know, serving Jehovah
faithfully for many decades
終わりまで忍耐しなければ
価値がありません
is only valuable
if we ‘endure to the end.’
エホバへの熱烈な愛を
育むことにより—
By developing
intense love for Jehovah,
どんな誘惑や試練も
克服することができます
we’ll be able to overcome
whatever temptations or trials we face.
And speaking
of enduring to the end,
終わりまで耐え忍ぶことに関して—
Brother Mark Sanderson recently spoke
at morning worship in Bethel
マーク・サンダーソン兄弟は
最近の朝の崇拝で—
エホバの日を切なる期待を
抱いて待つことが—
about how our eager expectation
of the day of Jehovah
この体制で忠実に耐え忍ぶ
助けとなるという点を扱われました
will help us to endure faithfully
in this system of things.
では その期待を示す幾つかの方法
について注意深く学びましょう
Pay close attention
to some of the ways
we show such expectation.
Well, here’s the question
we want to ask this morning:
今朝 お尋ねしたい質問があります
Is it actually possible
to speed up the day of Jehovah?
エホバの日を実際に速めることは
できるでしょうか?
Well, if we look at our text this morning
今日の聖句の
ペテロ第二 3:11をご覧ください
at 2 Peter 3:11,
先ほど読んだ部分ですが そこには—
we’ve had that read for us,
so we know
that expression at the end
“聖なる行状と敬虔な専心のうちに”—
that we should “consider
what sort of people you ought to be
自分がどのような者となるべきかを
考えるよう勧められています
in holy acts of conduct
and deeds of godly devotion.”
But then it goes on to say:
そしてこう続いています
“エホバの日の臨在を待ち—”
“As you await and keep close in mind
“それをしっかりと思いに
留める者となるべき”です
the presence of the day of Jehovah.”
Well, now, if you look at the footnote
12節の脚注を見ると
“しっかりと思いに留める” とは—
on this expression in verse 12,
you’ll notice that the expression
字義的には
エホバの日を“速める” という意味です
“keep close in mind” literally means
to “speed up” the day of Jehovah.
Well, now, how can we do that?
どのようにそうできますか?
Well, it’s true we cannot bring
わたしたちは
エホバの日の到来を一日たりとも—
the day forward of Jehovah
even one day,
速めたり遅らせたりすることは
できません
nor can we move it
back even one day.
それはできません
すでに決まっています
That is not within our power.
That day is set.
But how can we, then,
“speed up”
しかし どうすれば12節が
述べているように—
エホバの日を“速める”こと
ができるでしょうか?
the day of Jehovah
as it says there in verse 12?
Well, we keep that day
close in our mind.
その日をしっかりと思いに留めるのです
We never let it be out of our sight.
決してその日から
目をそらさないことです
As the footnote also says,
脚注には その日を
“熱烈に願い求める”ともあります
we “eagerly desire” it.
Well, now,
if we’re persons like that,
ペテロによると
そのような人は—
“敬虔な専心”という
行ないにおいて忙しい人です
Peter says
that we’re going to be busy
in “deeds of godly devotion.”
Well, now,
just as a quick reminder:
敬虔な専心とは
どういう意味だったでしょうか?
What is godly devotion?
Well, just looking
at our New World Translation glossary,
新世界訳聖書の
用語集の定義によると—
here’s the definition:
それは“エホバの宇宙主権に対する
忠誠を伴う エホバ神に対する—”
It’s “reverence, worship,
“and service to Jehovah God,
“崇敬 崇拝 奉仕”です
with loyalty
to his universal sovereignty.”
Well, what do we get
from that definition?
この定義から何が分かりますか?
Did you notice
—reverence, worship, service?
崇敬 崇拝 奉仕が関係しています
You see, godly devotion
is not passive; it’s active.
敬虔な専心は受動的なものではなく
能動的なものなのです
It’s reflected
in action and in activity.
それは行動や活動に表われます
Well, that’s why the apostle Peter
ですから使徒ペテロは11節で—
used the expression in verse 11,
“敬虔な専心の” 行ないについて
述べたのです
“deeds of godly devotion.”
Well, what are some of the ways
that we demonstrate this quality?
この特質をどのような方法で
示せるでしょうか?
Well, some of them are just very small.
ちょっとしたことで示せます
For example, what about hospitality?
もてなすことはどうですか?
At 1 Peter 4:9,
ペテロは最初の手紙を書いたとき
ペテロ第一 4:9で—
when the apostle Peter
wrote his first letter, he said:
“愚痴を言うことなく互いを
暖かくもてなしなさい”と言いました
“Be hospitable
to one another without grumbling.”
Well, there are
so many opportunities
必要に応じて他の人と分け合うために—
for us to imitate Jehovah
and be hospitable
エホバに倣って人をもてなす機会は
非常に多くあります
—to share with others
according to their needs.
それはほかの人に対してだけでなく—
And this really is an expression
not only for another person
エホバに対する愛の表現でもあり
神に見倣いたいとの願いの表われです
but it’s an expression
of our love for Jehovah
—our desire to want
to imitate him.
その通りです
Well, we all acknowledge that.
でも質問があります
But here’s the question:
When was the last time
あなたが最近人をもてなしたのは
いつのことでしたか?
that you acted hospitably?
そしてわたしは
どうだったでしょうか?
Or when was the last time
I acted hospitably?
You see, it’s not enough just to love
the quality of hospitality.
人をもてなす特質を愛するだけでは
十分ではありません
If we are going
to have deeds of godly devotion,
敬虔な専心を行ないで示したいなら
それを実践しなければなりません
we’re going to have to practice it.
Here’s another one.
ほかにもあります
What about helping the elderly
that are in our midst?
年長の人たちを助けることについては
どうでしょうか?
You know,
our elderly brothers need help.
年長の人たちは助けを必要としています
They need help
to get to the meetings.
集会に行くのにも 野外奉仕に
出かけるにも助けが必要です
They need help
to get out in the field ministry.
Some of them
are confined to their homes.
家から出られない人もいます
Well, if that’s the case,
they may need help from younger ones
もしそうなら 若い人たちが
買い物を手伝ったり用事を果たしたり—
to assist them
with shopping or doing errands
家の周りの雑用をしたりして
援助できるかもしれません
or just doing
some chore around the house.
そのことは「ものみの塔」誌の
多くの記事の中で言及されてきました
Well, that’s something
that has been mentioned
in many Watchtower articles.
大会でもたびたび
話されてきましたし—
It’s been mentioned
at many conventions and assemblies.
会衆の集会でも幾度も扱われました
It’s been mentioned
at many congregation meetings.
では質問です
年長の兄弟や姉妹のために—
But now here’s a question:
When was the last time
最近あなたが何かをしてあげたのは
いつのことですか?
that you did something
for an elderly brother or sister?
Or when was the last time I did?
わたしはどうだったでしょうか?
You see, we need to think
わたしたちはこうした考えを
好むだけでなく—
about not just loving these ideas
本当に助けになるために自分は
何をしているかを考える必要があります
but what are we doing to really help?
See, that’s showing
deeds of godly devotion.
それが敬虔な専心を
行ないで示すことなのです
Well, of course, we also have to think
about the more major things.
もちろん さらに重要な事柄についても
考える必要があります
What about attending
our congregation meetings?
会衆の集会に出席することについては
どうですか?
Hebrews 10:23-25
幾度も引用される聖句
ヘブライ 10:23-25は—
—that scripture
that we quote so many times—
says that we should ‘not forsake
our meeting together.’
“集まり合うことをやめ[ない]”
ようにと述べています
しかし続けて
“互いに励まし合い”なさいと述べています
But it goes on to say
that we should ‘encourage one another.’
So it’s not enough
just to be at the meeting.
ですから集会に来るだけでは
不十分です
When we’re there, we want to reach out
and do everything that we can
集会では兄弟たちを励ますために
できることは何でも行なうよう努力し—
to encourage our brothers
and really participate in the meeting.
本当の意味で
参加したいと思います
You see, godly devotion
is not passive; it’s active.
敬虔な専心は
受動的ではなく能動的です
And so, what sort of persons ought we to be
when we’re at the meeting?
では集会ではどんな人に
なるべきだと思いますか?
Well, we know we want to be active,
活発でプログラムに十分参加する人に
なりたいと思います
fully involved with the program.
But now, of course,
what’s the most important way
しかし敬虔な専心を実践するための
最も重要な方法は何でしょうか?
that we exercise
these deeds of godly devotion?
Well, you’ll remember
that the apostle Paul
使徒パウロはテモテ第一 3:16で—
at 1 Timothy 3:16
“敬虔な専心に関する神聖な奥義”
について言及しましたが—
referred to ‘the sacred secret
of godly devotion,’
パウロはイエスがまさにその奥義である
ことを明らかにしました
and he showed there
that Jesus really was that secret.
You see, he was
the one who demonstrated
イエスは完全な意味で
敬虔な専心を示した人でした
godly devotion
in a perfect sense.
Now, Paul in that verse,
1 Timothy 3:16,
パウロはさらに
そのテモテ第一 3:16の中で—
went on to say that Jesus
was ‘preached among the nations.’
イエスが“諸国民の中で
宣べ伝えられた”と述べました
Well, then, that really is
a vital part
ですから キリスト・イエス
その王国—
of our deeds of godly devotion
また実現するすべての事柄について
宣べ伝えることは—
—preaching about Christ Jesus,
his Kingdom,
敬虔な専心の重要な部分を
占めているのです
and everything
that will be accomplished.
But brothers,
how much incentive we have today
では兄弟たち 今日宣べ伝える業に
十分あずかるための—
動機付けとなるものが
どれほどあるでしょうか?
to be involved fully
in our preaching work.
わたしたちにはかつてなかったほどの
様々な道具があります
We have tools today
like we have never had before.
You know, over the summer
as I was attending
夏のあいだ わたしは世界の
様々な場所で開催される—
a number of different regional conventions
in different parts of the world,
多くの地区大会に出席しました
I enjoyed so much,
no doubt just as you have,
皆さんもきっとそうだと思いますが—
JW Libraryアプリを使って
良い経験ができました
using the JW Library app
and downloading
the Why Study the Bible? video
いくつもの言語で—
「聖書を学ぶべきなのはなぜですか」の
ビデオをダウンロードして活用しました
in a number of different languages.
We had one real interesting experience
when we were in Europe.
ヨーロッパで
本当に興味深い経験をしました
We got into a taxi
with a driver from Africa.
アフリカ人の運転する
タクシーに乗りました
それで すぐその人の母語は何か
聞いてみました
And right away,
we asked him what his language was.
Well, he told us it was
a language not familiar to us at all.
あなたたちが知らない言語だ
という返事でした
But while he was driving,
でもタクシーの中で—
we managed to download
the Why Study the Bible? video,
「聖書を学ぶべきなぜですか」の
ビデオを何とかダウンロードすると—
and it automatically
began to play as we were in the car.
運転中にビデオが自動的に
再生されてしまいました
Well, as soon as the man heard it,
he started shouting:
ビデオが流れるとすぐ
その人は—
“What’s happening?
What’s happening?”
“一体何が起きたんですか”
と叫び出しました
I think he thought
he was hearing a voice from heaven
この人はタクシーの中で
自分の言語を聞いたとき—
when he heard
his own language in the taxi.
天からの声だ
と思ったかもしれません
But we reassured him
that that was not the case.
でもそうではないことを
よく説明しました
But he was so moved.
心を動かされたこの人は—
He almost didn’t want to take the fare,
if you can imagine,
なかなかタクシー代を
受け取ろうとはしませんでした
最初全く友好的ではなかった人がです
and initially
he had been quite unfriendly.
But when he saw
what was available on our website,
ウェブサイトから入手できるものに
ついて知った時—
he was deeply moved.
とても感動していました
Well, maybe
you’ve had a similar experience.
皆さんも同様の経験をして
おられることでしょう
Just as a note of future reference:
でも 運転中にビデオを流すのはあまり
良いことではないかもしれませんね
It’s probably not a good idea
to play the video
when someone is driving.
Well, if we have
real godly devotion that’s active,
活動的な本当の
敬虔な専心があれば—
それを行ないで示す点で
忙しくなることでしょう
we’re going to be busy
in doing deeds of godly devotion.
You know,
there’s an old saying that says:
古いことわざに 楽しい時は
すぐに過ぎるというのがあります
“Time flies when you’re having fun.”
Well, you know, even scientists
acknowledge that there’s truth in that.
科学者たちもその言葉が真実である
ことを認めています
A study that was published
in the year 2012
2012年発行の「心理科学」という
雑誌に載った研究はこう述べています
in the journal
Psychological Science said this:
Although we tend to believe
楽しい時間は速くたってしまうと
考えがちだが—
that time flies
when we’re having a good time,
these studies
indicate that what it is
何がそう感じさせるのかという
ことが研究によってわかってきた
about the enjoyable time
that causes it to go by more quickly.
それは追い求める目標
あるいは—
It seems to be the goal pursuit
or achievement-directed action
we’re engaged in that matters.
一生懸命努力して成し遂げた事柄である
と考えられる
Just being content or satisfied
may not make time fly,
ただ満ち足りて満足するだけでは
時間が速くたつとは感じない
but being excited or actively pursuing
だが熱心に目標を追い求めるなら
時間はすぐに過ぎ去ってしまう
a desired object can.
Isn’t that interesting?
興味深いですね
Well, now, if we’re
the sort of persons that are busy
永遠の命という最も重要な目標を
目指して—
with holy acts of conduct
and deeds of godly devotion,
聖なる行状と敬虔な専心の行ないにおいて
忙しい人となるよう努力するなら—
reaching out for that most important goal
of everlasting life,
心と思いの中でエホバの日の到来を
速めることができるでしょう
we will speed up the coming
of the day of Jehovah
in our hearts and our minds.
What deeds of godly devotion
敬虔な専心の行ないについて
どんな点を学べましたか？
do you remember
from that fine presentation?
サンダーソン兄弟は
その一つが—
Among other things,
Brother Sanderson explained
互いをもてなすことである
と説明してくださいました
that one deed of godly devotion
is to be hospitable to one another.
“もてなし”は 今月のミュージック
ビデオのテーマでもあります
Hospitality is also the theme
of this month’s music video,
タイトルは
“もてなすことに努めよう”です
which is entitled
“Follow the Course [of Hospitality].”
お食事とクッキーとコーヒー
It might be a meal or snacks or coffee
Or fun and games, maybe just talking.
おしゃべりとかゲームも
Jehovah is the one who put it on our table.
So could we be able . . .
エホバは すべてをくださるの
だからできるわ・・・
迎えよう　心こめて
“Follow the course of hospitality.”
Imitate God above.
神にならい
Do it with true impartiality.
That’s what it means to love.
かたよらずに みんなを
それが愛なの
このおうちは エホバからのもの
The roof above our heads
is from our heavenly Father.
だれかを 泊めてあげられるかな？
But if we need to share,
would it be a bother?
Let’s feel the joy
that only ever comes from giving!
与えると 幸せになるの
That’s Christian living.
ステキなことね
迎えよう　心こめて
“Follow the course of hospitality.”
Imitate God above.
神にならい
かたよらずに みんなを
Do it with true impartiality.
That’s what it means to love.
それが愛なの
何もかもなくした　友がいる
Some people don’t have what we have.
It’s up to us to share.
ほほ濡らす涙　そっと拭いて
Disaster strikes, then they’re without.
Will we really care?
部屋をあけて 迎えてあげる？
Could we open up our home
and host a friend in need?
手を引いて
Do a kindly deed.
“Follow the course of hospitality.”
Imitate God above.
迎えよう　心こめて
神にならい
Do it with true impartiality.
That’s what it means to love.
かたよらずに みんなを
それが愛なの
That’s what it means to love.
素晴らしい歌でしたね！
What a nice song!
And while that music video
brings this program to its conclusion,
このミュージックビデオで
プログラムを結ぶ前に—
お勧めしたいビデオがあります
we’d like to encourage you to watch a video
それは シンディー・マッキントッシュ姉妹に
関するもので—
that will be posted later this month
about Sister Cindy McIntosh.
今月後半に公開されます
She was in the military for many years
長年 軍隊にいた姉妹は—
自分が “陰険で 愛情に欠けた人”に
なっていったと述べています
and described herself as having become
a “dark and uncaring person.”
しかし彼女は 真の愛を
エホバから学びました
But then Jehovah taught her
what true love means.
このビデオのタイトルは
“わたしはライフルを捨てました” です
The video is entitled I Put Down My Rifle
and is available on Video on Demand
ビデオ・オンデマンドの
“経験とインタビュー”でご覧になれます
in the “Interviews
and Experiences” category.
Yes, love truly is
the identifying mark of true Christians.
確かに愛は 真のクリスチャンを
見分けるしるしです
旅行などで他の会衆を訪問すると
その愛が際立っていることがわかります
That’s what stands out
when you
visit other congregations,
perhaps when traveling.
One good example
is the Nong Khai Congregation
その良い例は タイの北東部に
ある ノンカイ会衆です
in the northeastern corner of Thailand.
32名の伝道者から
愛が送られています
The 32 publishers send their love.
There’s a great need in Thailand,
タイは 必要が非常に大きく—
この会衆の 10名の任命された
兄弟たちと—
which is why half
of the 10 appointed brothers
in the congregation
and half of the 18 pioneers
18名の開拓者たちの半数は
必要のために移動してきました
are “need greaters.”
証言用のカートは
国境近くに置かれていて—
Witnessing carts have been set up
at a nearby border crossing,
出版物が10の言語で
提供されています
with ten languages
regularly featured.
業が制限されている国からの訪問者にも
多く配布されています
Many copies
are placed with visitors
from countries
where our work is restricted.
ここでは 一日に1,000冊以上の
出版物が配布されることもあります
Sometimes over 1,000 pieces of literature
are placed in a single day
at the border crossing.
ノンカイ会衆は 昨年10月に開かれた
特別大会の際に—
The Nong Khai Congregation
had the privilege
of being a host congregation
when a special convention
ホストの会衆として 出席者を
迎える特権にあずかりました
was arranged
in October of last year.
And during the convention,
they were surprised and overjoyed to hear
その大会では 新世界訳聖書がタイ語で
入手できるようになったことが発表され—
that the New World Translation
was now available
兄弟たちは
驚きと喜びに満たされました
in the Thai language.
エホバがこれからも タイの兄弟姉妹を
祝福してくださるよう祈っています
We pray that Jehovah continues to bless
the brothers and sisters in Thailand.
And all of you around the world,
we love you very much!
わたしたちは 世界中にいる
皆さんを 心から愛しています
This is JW Broadcasting
from Brooklyn, New York.
ニューヨーク市 ブルックリンから
JW Broadcastingでした